<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;रामानुज-नित्य-ग्रन्थः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/vaiShNavaH/shrI-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;रामानुज-नित्य-ग्रन्थः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/vaiShNavaH/shrI-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clooney</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/vaiShNavaH/shrI-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/Clooney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/vaiShNavaH/shrI-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/Clooney/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Rāmānuja’s Nityagrantham (“Manual of Daily Worship”): A Translation
Francis X. Clooney
0 Translator’s Preface Rāmānuja (1017–1137) was a philosopher and theologian; a saint and mystic, a lover of God; a proponent of the harmony of Tamil and Sanskrit traditions; and a premier leader of the South Indian Hindu Śrīvaiṣṇava community and a reformer of its ritual practices. Nine works are attributed to him:
Vedārthasaṃgraha, on the right interpretation of the Upaniṣads and the right use of them in the theological and spiritual practice of the devotee; the Gītābhāṣya, commentary on the Bhagavad Gītā; the Śrībhāṣya, commentary on the Brahmasūtras; 4–5) the Vedāntadīpā and the Vedāntasāra (summaries of Rāmānuja’s reading the Brahmasūtras); (6–8) three long prose prayers of surrender to Nārāyaṇa with the Goddess Śrī— surrender to God within oneself: Śaraṇāgatigadya, surrender at the temple: Śrīraṅgagadya, and surrender eschatologically, in heaven: Śrīvaikuṇṭhagadya; and the Nitya grantham or Nityam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mūlam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/vaiShNavaH/shrI-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/mUlam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/vaiShNavaH/shrI-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/mUlam/</guid>
      <description>English I. The Purpose of the Nityam: The Daily Practice of the Person Who Has Already Taken Refuge
अथ परमैकान्तिनो भगवदाराधनप्रयोगं वक्ष्ये ।
English I will now set forth (the performance of) the adoration of the Lord by the person single-mindedly focused on the Highest1.
English Part One: Routine Preparations, Recollection of the Act of Taking Refuge, and Interior Preparations
भगवत्कैङ्कर्यैकरतिः, परमैकान्ती भूत्वा
स्नानम् &amp;ldquo;भगवानेव स्वशेषभूतेन मया
स्वकीयैश् च देहेन्द्रियान्तःकरणैः, स्वकीयैर् एव कल्याणतमैर् औपचारिक-सांस्पर्शिकाभ्य्-अवहारिकैः भोगैः,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
